Roman Parkhomenko

Senior Software Engineer

Personal Info

Address

7211 Sedgerock Ln. Colorado Springs, CO 80927

Phone

719-930-9030

E-mail

rsparkhomenko@gmail.com

WWW

romanparkhomenko.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/roman-parkhomenko/

Skills

JavaScript / JQuery

React

HTML5

SCSS / CSS3

PHP

C# / .NET

Java

Wordpress / CMS

Senior Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience building enterprise websites and applications. Highly performant and driven individual committed to providing high quality work. Emphasized skillset in front-end technology with the ability to navigate the full-stack.

Experience

2021-07 - Senior Software Engineer

present

BombBomb

- Architected access level infrastructure for rapid feature set management across products.
- Managed permutational growth loop experiments across several systems to increase product conversion and usage.
- Consolidated RESTful API endpoints, increased test coverage, and centralized process for flexible billing scenarios.
- Maintained billing system responsible for over 1M successful transactions annually.

2019-07 - **Software Engineer**

2021-07

BombBomb

- Modularized and rearchitected payment processing forms to atomic components to decrease billing errors.
- Engineered new solutions to track key company metrics with a client-side approach.
- Developed infrastructure across marketing website and application to automatically assign customer plans.
- Created growth loop to increase product trial signups by 100%.
- Improved internal tooling to remove customer success and sales need for billing system access.

2016-12 - Front End Development Lead

2019-07

BombBomb

- Implemented new website performance strategies for a projected increase of \$700,000 in annual recurring revenue due to load time reductions.
- Oversaw development for brand overhaul with numerous key pages, while ensuring optimized SEO and technical performance, resulting in a 30% increase of conversion rate and traffic to website.
- Managed Wordpress hosting migration to cloud based service, drastically streamlining development workflow.
- Rebuilt customer payment processing between the application and website without using framework dependencies.
- Optimized event tracking for more accurate data reporting in Google Analytics.

2015-03 - **Co-Founder**

2020-07

ThinkSpark.io

- Identify client needs to deliver responsive, optimal web and marketing solutions.
- Create custom configurations for WordPress to ensure client autonomy after project completion.
- Establish infrastructure to optimize post and page SEO automatically.

Education

2017-04 **Grand Canyon University**

• Bachelors of Science in Computer Programming